Spencer Lindemuth

Inspired developer with passion for creating engaging, easy to use websites. I successfully leverage my eagerness to learn, bright personality, and 8 years of technical background to lead the creation of complex sites and systems in an efficient, timely manner, using the latest trends in technology. With experience in software development, web design, information technology, and systems administration, I am a full stack candidate for any team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Javascript, React, HTML/CSS, Ruby, Rails, Active Record, Python, Java, PHP, WordPress, PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, Photoshop, Lightroom, XD, Heroku, Azure, Netlify, IIS, Apache, Active Directory, Windows Group Policy

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

CSSchool - Github | Website

A website designed to teach CSS basics to people of all ages in an interactive learning environment

- Utilized React to create a guiz-based learning environment teaching CSS to beginners to intermediate students
- Built feature allowing users to dynamically generate custom lessons through an HTML form
- Developed program to be seamlessly used on mobile using CSS media queries
- Constructed Rails backend API to serve lessons and handle JWT authentication

Hi-Lo - Github | Website

A turn based, two player game based on the popular card game Acey Deucey

- Created multiplayer game with pure javascript frontend and game logic
- Deployed app to accrue over 100 games played by more than 50 unique users
- Optimized game to play effortlessly on desktop and mobile

Artsy Fartsy - Github | Website

A website that allows users to create their own digital gallery of select works from the MET™ museum

- Designed React app using React-Draggable to place and persist pieces on gallery wall
- Employed MET OpenAccess API™ to find public domain works to browse and add to gallery
- Utilized a mix of traditional and on trend design elements to create an engaging experience for modern users

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Hotel Monaco Seattle, WA

Valet/Doorman

January 2016 - May 2019

- Exceeded guest expectations of service, maintaining highest hotel department feedback score, over 96% all three years
- Developed friendly, welcoming presence with which to great guests upon arrival
- Performed exemplary retrieval times for cars and luggage which maintained a clear and orderly lobby and parking zone

Northside Networks Mesa, AZ

I.T. Support/Systems Administration

October 2012 - May 2014

- Delivered 24/7 guick response services for more than 40 small businesses simultaneously
- Maintained excellent record of minimizing and preventing downtime and loss of business
- Deployed Small Business Servers for user management, email, hosting, and content distribution
- Mastered a working knowledge of computers, servers, networking equipment and other hardware and how they function

Clearcut Marketing Concepts

Mesa. AZ

Junior Developer

June 2011 - October 2012

- Filled gap between front-end and back-end developer learning both UX/UI design and PHP server architecture
- Utilized CSS to style PHP front-end e-commerce websites
- Integrated seamlessly into an existing small team to quickly and reliably create content

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Seattle, WA

2010-2012

2019

University of Michigan

Ann Arbor, MI

Computational Informatics (2 years toward B.S.)

Full Stack Software Engineering

- Achieved intermediate proficiency of Python and beginner proficiency with C++